<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Blavi Josa, Laia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pérez Hernández, José Francisco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Solà Oriol, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Maternal learning and Creep-Feeding: two strategies determining the post-weaning performance of piglets</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/12612</dc:identifier>
  <dc:subject>creep-feed</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>maternal learning</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>flavour</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>piglet</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>preferences</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:description>The early exposure of foetus to certain volatiles may result in a further preference for these compounds later in life and can positively affect the further acceptance of food containing a similar flavour. The study consisted in three trials: 1) determination of the effects on piglet performance of flavour supplementation in sow’s diets (late gestation and lactation) and in weaning diets; 2) creep-feed consumption and preference evaluation by a double choice test (DCHT) comparing the studied flavour and a negative control; 3) identification of the independent role of flavour inclusion in late gestation or lactation throughout DCHT. The inclusion of flavour in sow’s diets improved piglets’ appetite when same flavour was included at weaning. The positive reward associated to the flavour included in sow’s diet was stronger when piglets were offered a non-flavoured creep-feed. Exposure to flavour only at the end of gestation would be enough to condition the piglets.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>