<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Valentín Solanas, Ana Cristina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Luzón Marco, María José</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Inglés de negocios como lengua franca: implicaciones pedagógicas</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/56990</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2016</dc:date>
  <dc:description>English as a Lingua Franca has contributed to the breaching of international language barriers, affecting almost every aspect of our life. Business is not an exception, thus its users have also take advantage of the use of English to create a common bond among the business community. It resulted in the coinage of the term BELF (Business English as a Lingua Franca), which as any other ESP, encompasses certain types of vocabulary or communication strategies that are shared by BELF users. However, what is of utmost relevance is the called “business know-how”, an indispensable requisite any successful BELF user must be in possession of.  For this reason, BELF users demand a type of English teaching that cannot be fulfilled merely with the traditional general English teaching. Therefore, teachers need to look for more specific and useful ways to teach the kind of English BELF users will encounter within their environment and thus, need to master. This paper explores some possibilities that could be suitable when designing a BELF-oriented lesson.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>