<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Curdi Cepero, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marcuello Pablo, Juan José</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Analysis, design and implementation of grid connected PV inverter system</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/11864</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Solar power holds great potential for the future in the realm of renewable energy. The solar energy has room for improvement, due to the low efficiency of the solar panels. It can be implemented everywhere from calculators, buildings, cars, etc. Solar energy is a field that has to be studied and continually researched until the maximum efficiency is reached. This project can help for further developments in photovoltaic system components. This thesis focused on the implementation and design of the components of a photovoltaic system. These components are the MPP tracker, different topologies of DC-DC converters and inverters connected to the grid. More specifically, the implementation of an MPP tracker algorithm, and boost converter was carried out at the end of this thesis. For the algorithm of the maximum power point tracker, the Perturb and Observe algorithm has been used. It is one of the most used algorithms due to its simplicity of its implementation with analogue and digital circuits. After the MPP tracker, the boost converter has been designed in relation to the objective of this project of feeding electricity to the grid. The boost converter will increase the voltage of the solar panel so then it can be transformed from DC to AC, and transformed with different controls synchronized to the grid.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>