<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Obi,Vitus Ikechukwu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Barriuso Vargas, Juan</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Evaluation of Four Botanical Fungicides and Situational Review on Vigna ungiculata(L.Walp.) Anthracnose pathogen, Colletotrichum spp. Sacc &amp; Mang.</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/9889</dc:identifier>
  <dc:subject>botanical</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>biopesticides</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>vigna unguiculata,</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>colletotrichum destructivum</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>anthracnose,</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>cowpea</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:description>ABSTRACT  The completion of this research involved the revision of about seventy one referred subject related journals and academic materials. The parasitic organism Colletotrichum destructivum O`Gara was associated as the actual causal pathogen of cowpea anthracnose. Of all the twenty different pathogens linked with the various cowpea fungal diseases, in this work, only Colletotrichum (C. destructivum) was found to have the virulence and propensity of afflicting a 100% infection on a single susceptible cowpea crop each at a given pathogenic situation. Twenty Colletotrichum species along with their specific primary hosts were identified in this work. The study also provided eighteen plant families under the pathogenic affliction of Colletotrichum identified alongside eighteen different plant families representing the entire plants and plant materials screened for biofungicidal properties within a span of eleven years. The screened botanicals of four plants of Azadiractha indica, Cymbopogon citratus, Ocimum gratissimum, and Xylopia aethiopica were effective in reducing the spore germination and radial growth of Colletotrichum destructivum O`Gara in vitro and the growth of the pathogen in vivo. Cold water botanicals of C. citratus were the best in reducing the growth of the pathogen in vitro and in checking the spread of anthracnose disease of cowpea in vivo. An evaluation with cowpea (Vigna unguiculata) indicated the extracts applied before or after pathogen inoculation to be significantly effective in reducing the size of pathogen induced lesion.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>