<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Ferruz Gracia, Pedro Pablo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Esteban Sánchez, Ana Lucía</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>PRODUCT DESIGN, DEVELOPMENT AND VIABILITY ANALYSIS MOTORCYCLE HELMET. LIGHT SECURITY SYSTEM “DragonFlight”</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/32635</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Every single one of us have heard ones or know someone who have had a bad experience with a motorbike, maybe it was his or her fault, perhaps it was originated due to the mistake of other vehicle or just was a simple distraction that caused as a result that small fright or that horrible accident. All the people who ride motorcycles assume that when an impact comes, our body is the chassis, our own body is in jeopardy to the unexpected just protected with a helmet and some protection clothes. The main goal of this project will be to try to reduce the possibilities of motorcycle users of having a fatality accident or at least reduce the gravity of them. We are going to create and develop a device to install in our helmets that turn on lights if the helmet and obviously “the biker” is decelerating. We will set up an emergency system as well in cases when the biker falls when we’ll show up as much lights as possible. The number of lights and as a result the intensity of the view are going to increase with the percentage of deceleration, this means that if the biker do an small deceleration we are just going to show a little light up however if the biker do a huge deceleration we will show an alarming and easy to see light in our helmet reducing then the perception and reaction time of the vehicles behind us. Our objective is to create a portable dispositive to be able to use it in more than one helmet so you as biker only have to buy one for all your helmets or to share with your family and friends.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>