<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Yurusen, Ismail Cem</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martín Solans, Santiago</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cea Mingueza, Pilar</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Uso de electrodos basados en el carbono para la fabricación de dispositivos electrónicos</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/63592</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
  <dc:description>The research on the development of electronic devices is growing as fast as ever. As new challenges arise with the continuous miniaturisation of electronic components, nanostructured and carbon-based materials have been become very promising for future developments and products. In this project, an all-carbon molecular electronic device, which is completely free of metals, is reported. A Langmuir film of graphene oxide (GO) was fabricated and characterised by using a Brewster angle microscope (BAM). Then, transferences of a GO  Langmuir-Blodgett (LB) film onto mica substrate for different transference conditions were carried out. Morphology of the samples were characterised by using an atomic force microscope (AFM). Once the optimum transference conditions of GO LB film were determined, electrografting processes of Oligo(Phenylene Ethynylene) (OPE) derivatives onto highly oriented pyrolytic graphite (HOPG) substrate were carried out. After monolayers of OPE derivatives onto HOPG were confirmed by using various characterisation techniques such as Raman spectroscopy, AFM and cyclic voltammetry (CV), transferences of GO LB film onto modified HOPG substrates were carried out. Future work to achieve all-carbon molecular electronic devices is also explained.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>