<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>VILLAR ALDONZA, ADRIANO</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gómez Sancho, José María </dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mancebón, María Jesús</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>EVALUACIÓN DEL IMPACTO DE LA ESCOLARIZACIÓN TEMPRANA SOBRE LAS HABILIDADES COGNITIVAS Y NO COGNITIVAS DE LOS NIÑOS DE 5 AÑOS</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/32535</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:description>This project explores how starting school at a younger age affects the achievement at the age of six years.  For that, we employed data from a  pilot report. Once we improved that database, we calculated a propensity score for each student, that is, the likelihood that each individual has to attend early education. This procced allowed us to avoid the trouble knows as selection bias, which could distort our results.  Using that propensity, we stratified the sample in 4 blocks in order to get a more homogeneous subgroups of students in all the characteristics that simultaneously could influence the participation in early education and the achievement of pupils. Finally, we run a regression in each of the before mentioned subgroups using a MCO estimation. The achievement at the age of six was the dependent variable in this regression and the attendance to early education the main predictor. In addition, the model incorporated a wide number of covariates. Previously to the empirical research, we reviewed the Economics of Education’ literature  related with the topic object of our attention,. In addition our report includes a proto-research which allows us to know the origin of early education in Sapin, as well a review of the current situation in Spain against Europe in relation to early childhood education. Our empirical results suggest that early school start, before three years, do not have a statistically significant effect on cognitive and non-cognitive abilities of six years old children. This conclusión is different from that obtained in the majority of previous studies that have study this topic in the international sphere (mainly in anglo-saxon countries). We venture that the divervenge between our results and those from other studies may be attributed to the differences in the cultural patters between the countries; in particular,to the differences about the role of the family (mothers) in the care of children.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>