<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Cuevas Casa, Henry David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fajo Pascual, María Marta</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Childhood obesity prevention: a review of multi-component interventions</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/30924</dc:identifier>
  <dc:subject>obesidad, niños, prevención. obesity, child, prevention</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:description>According to the World Health Organization, 65% of the world's population live in countries where overweight and obesity kill more people than underweight. Overweight and obesity are defined as excessive body fat accumulation that presents major risk factors for a number of chronic diseases, including diabetes, cardiovascular diseases and cancer. Obesity rates have increased in recent years. In fact, the epidemic rates have nearly doubled since 1980 worldwide (WHO, 2012).  Likewise, we have seen a dramatic increase of deaths associated to chronic diseases since then. As we know, health costs have increased as well. According to some estimates, the cost of obesity can represent up to 12% of health care budget in some countries (Aranceta, 2013). Thus, tackling this problem it is of great importance in order to reduce health costs and improve population´s health quality from now to future generations. According to Baidal (2012), the problem should be focused on early stages of life, being children the key age group In this research project, we planned to identify strategies that comprise a multi-component approach to effectively tackle obesity in schooled children.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>