<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Herrer Jiménez, Isabel Lucía</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ros Latienda, Blanca</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sierra Travieso, Teresa</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Thermosensitive and photopolymerizable hydrogels based on Pluronic F127</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/12274</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Here it is reported the design, synthesis and characterization of new Pluronic® F127 derivatives, with the ability to form thermosensitive and photopolymerizable hydrogels. These active hydrogels undergo a sol-to-gel transition by increasing the temperature in a physiologically important temperature range thus resulting attractive for biomedical applications and drug delivery systems. Pluronic® F127 has been functionalized with photoreactive groups and the obtained derivatives and their precursors have been fully characterized by conventional techniques. Then the aimed compounds have been processed as macroscopically molded hydrogels and as nanostructured hydrogels (nanogels). A highly crosslinked internal structure has been reached by the photopolymerization technique for the thermosensitive macroscopic hydrogels designed to act as cell scaffolds for cartilage repair. Swelling and degradation studies as well as their morphological characterization by SEM have been carried out. Concerning the nanostructured hydrogels (nanogels), after determining its critical micellar concentration and applying a photopolymerization process to fix the nanostructure, they have been characterized by TEM, SEM and DLS. Cell viability assays have been carried out for both types of system, the macroscopic hydrogel and the nanogel.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>