<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>García Pujades, Aída</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Onega, Susana</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>"In Her Own Right": Narrative Voice and Ideology in Angela Carter's "The Bloody Chamber"</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/47241</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:description>ABSTRACT The aim of this essay is to demonstrate how narrative voice and style change the ideology of the same story. In the decade of the 1960s, in a society in which equal rights between men and women continued to be questioned, Angela Carter wrote short stories based on folk tales but from a different perspective. She highlighted the figure of women in line with the feminist movement of the 1960s and in opposition to the traditional patriarchal ideology.  In "The Bloody Chamber", a story based on the folk tale "Blue Beard", Carter changed point of view and style in order to reflect her feminist ideology. She reverses the stereotyped roles of the characters and turns the protagonist into the narrator of her own story. Moreover, her mother represents feminism in itself since she challenges patriarchal ideas about women. So, she influences the protagonist's behaviour through the way she educates her and she is also her saviour at the end of the story. This fact means that the most important roles in the story, both of narrator and saviour, are carried out by women. This contrasts with Charles Perrault’s version of "Blue Beard", in which these roles are played by male characters while women are left behind as passive and secondary and voiceless characters. Thus, while the folk tale warned women about the terrible consequences of their actions, Carter claimed that women were victims of a patriarchal society in which men, despite of their atrocities, are represented as heroes and women were considered inferior to them. The narrative mode employed in each story reflects one or the other ideology. RESUMEN Este ensayo tiene como objeto mostrar cómo la voz y el estilo narrativo cambian la ideología de una misma historia. En la década de 1960, en una sociedad en la que la igualdad de derechos entre hombres y mujeres seguían siendo cuestionadas, Angela Carter escribió historias cortas basadas en cuentos tradicionales pero con un enfoque distinto, realzando la figura de la mujer según el movimiento feminista de los años 60 y en oposición a la tradicional ideología patriarcal. En "The Bloody Chamber", una historia basada en el cuento popular "Blue Beard", Carter hace un cambio de punto de vista y estilo narrativo para reflejar su ideología feminista. Invierte los roles estereotipados de los personajes y convierte a la protagonista en la narradora de su propia historia. Además, su madre es la que representa el feminismo en sí, ya que desafía las ideas patriarcales sobre las mujeres. Así, la madre influye en el comportamiento de la protagonista a través de la educación que le da y es su salvadora al final de la historia. Esto significa que los roles más importantes, tanto el de narradora como el de salvadora, son desarrollados por mujeres, contrastando con la versión de Charles Perrault de  "Blue Beard" en el que estos papeles son masculinos, quedando las mujeres como personajes pasivos en un segundo plano y sin voz. De este modo, mientras el cuento tradicional prevenía a las mujeres sobre las terribles consecuencias de sus actos, Carter defiende que las mujeres son víctimas de una sociedad patriarcal en la que los hombres, pese a sus atrocidades, son representados como héroes y las mujeres son consideradas inferiores a ellos. El modo narrativo utilizado en cada una de las historias refleja una u otra ideología.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>