<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Elizondo Castillo, Hellen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Irusta Alderete, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>SBA-15 nanoestructurada cargada con compuestos de aceites esenciales integrada en fibras fabricadas por electrospinning para aplicación en apósitos inteligentes: estudio de la actividad bactericida</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/63694</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
  <dc:description>The treatment of skin and soft tissue infections (SSTI) represent a significant financial and clinical treatment concern. Therefore, it is important to develop novel strategies to combat the SSTI and the associated microorganisms, which are the main obstacle in healing processes. In this study, an essential oil compound (EOC) loaded nanostructured SBA-15, with bactericidal action against Staphylococcus aureus was developed. Additionally, these EOC loaded SBA-15 particles were attached to electrospun polycaprolactone (PCL) fibers. In this system, silica support behaves as EOC carrier, while the PCL fibrous structure provides a matrix suitable for wound dressing application. The antimicrobial effect of essential oil compounds was evaluated by the Minimum Inhibitory Concentration (MIC) and Minimum Bactericidal Concentration (MBC) in vitro determination. Carvacrol and thymol exhibited the higher bactericidal activity with MBC values of 0.3 mg/mL, followed by cinnamaldehyde with 0.5mg/mL. Dispersed rod-shaped SBA-15 particles have been synthesized, with an external diameter of 138 nm, a length of 563 nm and pore volume of 1.5 cm3/g. Then, carvacrol, thymol, or cinnamaldehyde were loaded into SBA-15 by incipient wetness impregnation method with a highly concentrated EOC ethyl acetate solution, yielding loading efficiencies (LE) as high as 256.0 % for carvacrol, 267.5 % for thymol, and 205.7% for cinnamaldehyde. The release of loaded EOC was sustained for the first 48 h, with 68% and 64 % release for carvacrol and thymol composites, respectively. EOC loaded SBA-15 showed a strong bactericidal effect on S. aureus. Compared with pure compound, the nanocomposite resulted in the enhancement of bactericidal activity of tested EOC, due to the mesoporous materials contribute to the solubility improvement of poorly water soluble compounds and the sustained release profile. Furthermore, the attachment of thymol SBA-15 loaded nanocomposite on biocompatible PLC fibers via electrospinning, was confirmed by SEM. Images showed well distributed and dispersed rods on fibers surface. This work has resulted in the formation of SBA-15 rod-shaped carriers loaded with EOC with enhanced bactericidal properties, as a promising composite system capable of being attached to biopolymer fibers surface, to be used as a wound dressing with antimicrobial properties in order to develop more efficient dressings for wound healing.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>