<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Abellanas Giménez, Ricardo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Azcona Montoliu, María del Mar</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Never-Ending 1-Ups: Video Game Influences in the Narrative of Edge of Tomorrow</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/31918</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Español Los videojuegos se han convertido en una parte significativa de la cultura popular, y su influencia se está extendiendo progresivamente hacia otros medios. En este trabajo se examinan la relación entre las industrias del cine y el videojuego además del uso de estructuras narrativas inusuales con el propósito de analizar el uso del lenguaje del videojuego en la película Al filo del mañana (Edge of Tomorrow). Utilizando como punto de partida el videojuego de Nintendo 64 The Legend of Zelda: Majora’s Mask, este trabajo explora las convenciones del videojuego que se utilizan en la película y la ideología transmitida a través de las mismas. English Video games have become a prominent part of popular culture, and their influence is progressively extending to other mediums. In this paper, the relationship between the film and the video game industries, as well as the use of unusual narrative structures are examined in order to analyse the use of video game language in the film Edge of Tomorrow. Utilizing the Nintendo 64 video game The Legend of Zelda: Majora’s Mask as a starting point, it is explored how many of the video games conventions are used in the film and the ideology that is conveyed through the use of that language.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>