<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Isiegas Gracia, Alejandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Onega Jaén, Susana</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>DEFEATING PATRIARCHY: FEMINIST TRAITS IN ANGELA CARTER’S “THE BLOODY CHAMBER” DEFEATING PATRIARCHY: FEMINIST TRAITS IN ANGELA CARTER’S “THE BLOODY CHAMBER”</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/62714</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Abstract  Angela Carter (7 May 1940 – 16 February 1992) was a well-known British novelist. She belonged to Second-Wave Feminism (1960-1980) and was polemical regarding feminism and pornography. Her peculiar vision of the latter as a weapon for women to use against sexism and inequality between the genders was harshly criticised by those feminists who saw pornography as the source of her objectification and maledominance in society. Despite being a very versatile writer, her best works are the short stories. She devoted part of her career to the rewriting of children’s literary classics compiled from the oral tradition by authors such as Charles Perrault or the Grimm brothers, The Bloody Chamber and Other Stories is one of Carter's best works in this area. In this case I opted for “The Bloody Chamber” because as a child I was fascinated by “Bluebeard”, one of the first stories I read. My aim is to explain both the narrative and thematic changes Carter introduces and how they exemplify the new feminist literature that breaks with the literary tradition dominated by men. To do so, I focus on the most important aspects of the tale that are different in the versions of Charles Perrault and Angela Carter and try to justify why they make “The Bloody Chamber” a perfect example of feminist rewriting of a classical folk tale.   Resumen  Angela Carter (1940 – 1992) fue una conocida novelista británica. Perteneciente a la Segunda Ola de Feminismo (1960-1980), fue polémica en cuestiones de feminismo y pornografía. Su peculiar visión de esta última como un arma al servicio de las mujeres con la que derrotar el machismo y la desigualdad entre géneros fue duramente criticada por aquellas feministas que veían la pornografía únicamente como un arma represora que reforzaba la superioridad de los hombres en la sociedad. A pesar de ser una escritora muy versátil, sus mejores trabajos son los relatos cortos. Dedicó parte de su carrera a la rescritura de clásicos infantiles de la literatura, recopilados de la tradición oral por autores como Charles Perrault o los hermanos Grimm. The Bloody Chamber and Other Stories es uno de los mejores trabajos de Carter en este ámbito. En este caso me decanté por “The Bloody Chamber” porque desde pequeña me ha fascinado “Barba Azul”, uno de los primeros cuentos que leí. Mi intención es explicar los cambios tanto narrativos como temáticos que Carter introduce y cómo estos ejemplifican la nueva literatura feminista que rompen con la tradición literaria dominada por los hombres. Para ello, me centro en los aspectos más importantes del cuento, que son diferentes en las versiones de Charles Perrault y Angela Carter y trato de justificar por qué estos hacen de “The Bloody Chamber” un perfecto ejemplo de rescritura feminista de un cuento maravilloso tradicional.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>