<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Simón Porcar, Guillermo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liesa Carrera, Carlos Luis</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Estudio estratigráfico y estructural de los sedimentos neógneos al este de la Sierra del Pobo</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/64100</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
  <dc:description>The El Pobo Basin is a Cenozoic sedimentary basin placed within the El Pobo Depression, whose formation responds to erosive and tectonic processes. The area is limited at its margins by the Sierra de El Pobo (that separates our basin from the Teruel-Alfambra Basin) to the west, the Sierra de Gúdar to the east, the Aguilar del Alfambra anticlinorium to the north, and Mesozoic outcrops in the area near to Monteagudo del Castillo and Allepuz, to the south. Inside the El Pobo basin widespread outcrops of Cenozoic materials appear along two subbasins that are separated by the Ababuj anticline relief, which was created by the reactivation of Cretaceous extensional structures as compressive ones during de Alpine Orogeny. The objective of this work was to study these Cenozoic outcrops at their geological context, from sedimentological, structural and geomorphological viewpoints, in order to know if they can be considered as a proper basin, and to analyze the development and evolution of that hypothetic basin.  The Cenozoic materials of the El Pobo Depression were never studied in depth, only vaguely mapped and defined as a single unit. However, there exist many studies that analyze sedimentology and structure of adjacent Mesozoic and Cenozoic rocks. They have been useful in order to define the age of our basin, relating sediment characteristics with the present deformation structures and with the erosive surfaces along the depression. The procedure followed during the study of the basin consisted on a conscientious fieldwork, after bibliographic revision, recognizing the material features and their setting, and also their relationship with the deformation structures. Several data have been taken in order to elaborate the maps, the stratigraphic schemes and to analyze the stress system. Along this report the results for the work accomplished are reflected, showing several evidences of a proper basin evolution at the El Pobo Depression. The basin is divided into two sectors, separated by the mentioned Ababuj anticline. The sedimentological study for both sectors has showed different deposit devices for each one. The western subbasin presents a predominant alluvial character, with a concentric drainage, while in the eastern one the sediment characteristics indicate a fluvial-alluvial system, with an axial drainage orientated to the north. Within an isolated Cenozoic area at the north of the western subbasin (Muela de la Umbría), evidence of a lacustrine system has been noticed. In every sector of the basin an interpretation of megasequential evolution was made and correlated with the sequences interpreted by Ezquerro (2017) for the northern sector of the Teruel Basin. The relationship between Cenozoic materials and deformation structures indicates that sedimentation occurred within the framework of several extensional episodes. Also, at the depression and its surroundings we found indications of several erosive surfaces, among which the most remarkable are the SEI and the SEF (the last one divided into three surfaces). The SEF upper sublevel seems to mark the limit of sedimentation at most of the basin, and later the SEF itself leveled the tilted deposits. Between a surface and the next the sediments were deformed by an extensional episode. Only at the northern area of the basin the SEF itself could be the upper limit of basin filling. With all these data, and with the age of the SEI set at 11,2 Ma, and at 3,8 Ma and 3,5 Ma for the upper sublevel of SEF and the SEF itself, respectively (Ezquerro, 2017), we could frame the El Pobo basin between a lower limit placed at 9 Ma, and an upper limit at 3,8 Ma, with a possible continuation of sedimentation in the northern sector until 3,5 Ma.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>