<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Duce Sarasa, Violeta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martínez Falquina, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>"Crossing a Terrible Line": Cross-racial Ventriloquism and the Liberation of White and Black Women in Kathryn Stockett's The Help</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/47045</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:description>This Master Thesis analyzes Kathryn Stockett’s The Help (2009) from the perspective of neo-segregation narratives in order to explore the possibilities of this literary tradition. Firstly, this analysis focuses on the controversy about Stockett’s ventriloquism, the risks for a white author when writing in a voice from a different race and the liberating potential of the novel’s cross-racial representations to deconstruct racial frontiers. Secondly, a close analysis of the novel reveals the liberation of white and black women in the text centering the attention on the feminist awakenings of Aibileen, Minny and Skeeter, who liberate themselves from dominant stereotypes commonly reproduced in the American literary tradition such as the Mammy, the Sapphire, and the Southern Belle respectively. Thirdly, the analysis of the sorority between races, together with the awareness process of the white protagonist, reflects the possibility of liberation from social conservative standards that this sisterhood offers to both white and black characters, and it simultaneously calls readers’ attention to the still present gender and racial discrimination in the 21st century society. Thus, this thesis will try to demonstrate that neo-segregation narratives such as The Help, which attempt to know the other by transgressing racial frontiers, contribute to spread the message of racial understanding and can help to change the sexist and racist society in which we currently live. / En este trabajo se analiza la novela The Help (2009) de Kathryn Stockett desde el punto de vista del género de las nuevas narrativas de segregación, con el fin de explorar las posibilidades de dicha tradición literaria. En primer lugar, el análisis se centra en la polémica provocada por el uso de ventriloquía por parte de la autora, en los riesgos que conlleva escribir en la voz de una persona de diferente raza para una escritora blanca, y en el carácter liberador de estos cambios de raza que permiten deconstruir fronteras raciales. En segundo lugar, un análisis más profundo de la novela muestra la liberación de las mujeres blancas y negras centrándose en el despertar feminista de Aibileen, Minny y Skeeter, quienes de esta manera, consiguen liberarse de los estereotipos más frecuentes en la tradición literaria norteamericana como son la ‘Mammy’ y la ‘Sapphire’ para las mujeres afroamericanas o la ‘Southern Belle’ para las mujeres blancas de clase media-alta. En tercer lugar, el análisis de la sororidad entre mujeres de diferentes razas, junto con el despertar a la realidad racista de la protagonista blanca de la novela, reflejan cómo en esta amistad, tanto blancas como negras encuentran la posibilidad de liberarse de las normas sociales más conservadoras. De la misma manera, esta colaboración entre razas recuerda a los lectores que, en pleno siglo XXI, sigue existiendo discriminación racial y discriminación de género en las sociedades de todo el mundo. Por consiguiente, este trabajo intentará demostrar que novelas pertenecientes al género de ‘neo-segregation narratives’ como The Help, las cuales traspasan fronteras raciales para entender al ‘otro’, contribuyen a difundir el mensaje de entendimiento entre razas y también pueden ayudar a cambiar la sociedad sexista y racista en la que vivimos hoy en día.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>