<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Muñoz González, Esther</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Onega Jaén, Susana</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Escuchando al pasado en el silencio de una casa vacia. Trauma, pérdida y maternidad en Lost Children de Maggie Gee.</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/56860</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2016</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Abstract This essay analyses Maggie Gee’s novel Lost Children (1994) from the combined perspectives of feminist and trauma theories. It contends that the sudden disappearance of her teenage daughter triggers a psychological quest for the recovery of the protagonist’s own lost childhood, voice and self, shattered by a traumatic experience she had in her childhood. The analysis brings to the fore the middle-aged woman’s process of working through of this strongly repressed and dissociated childhood trauma and sets her life struggle within the context of her socio-cultural and familial background, which is that of a middle-class British woman in the second half of the twentieth century. The analysis shows that Alma’s behaviour is representative of the worries, expectations and impositions that contemporary children and women are subject to in our western society, still imbued by patriarchal models and rules of behaviour. Resumen Este ensayo analiza la novela Lost Children (1994) de Maggie Gee desde una perspectiva que combina las teorías feminista y de trauma. El ensayo sostiene que la inesperada desaparición de su hija adolescente desencadena el viaje psicológico de la protagonista hacia la recuperación de su propia niñez perdida, de su voz e identidad, destrozadas por una experiencia traumática que tuvo en la niñez. El análisis pone de manifiesto el proceso de sanación seguido por esta mujer madura para superar un trauma fuertemente reprimido y disociado desde su infancia y sitúa su lucha dentro su propio ámbito socio-cultural y familiar, es decir el de una mujer británica de clase media en la segunda mitad del siglo XX. El análisis muestra que el comportamiento de Alma es representativo de las preocupaciones, expectativas e imposiciones a que están sometidos los niños y mujeres en nuestra sociedad occidental, todavía imbuida por modelos y reglas de comportamiento patriarcal.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>