<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Puente José, Patricia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Corona Marzol, Isabel</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>TRANSLATION ON CONTROVERSIAL NEWS:  uses of translation techniques and the influence of tribalisation in news dealing with Gibraltar</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/56553</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2016</dc:date>
  <dc:description>El aumento del volumen de traducciones en prensa a lo largo de los últimos años y la influencia que esta ejerce en el desarrollo de la sociedad contemporánea confirma la necesidad de investigar el proceso de traducción periodística, especialmente en noticias que presentan puntos cultural y políticamente controvertidos. En este trabajo de fin de grado se analizarán las principales técnicas de traducción de El País para su versión inglesa El País in English de artículos que tratan sobre el 'conflicto' de Gibraltar. Además se establecerá una relación entre algunos usos de las técnicas de traducción y la tribalización. The increase in journalistic translation during the last years and the influence that translation exerts over contemporary societies justify the importance of investigating the process of journalistic translation, especially if the news to translate deal with controversial issues. In this dissertation I analyse the translation techniques which the Spanish newspaper El País uses in  the translation of news about the 'conflict' of Gibraltar, published afterwards in El País English Edition. I also establish a relation between some uses of translation techniques and tribalisation.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>