<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>García Viñado, Violeta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Castro Escario, Elisenda</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>A comparative study of two theoretical and practical approaches related to ESL/ EFL</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/31067</dc:identifier>
  <dc:subject>innovative approaches</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>active learning</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>co-operative and collaborative learning</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>monitor model</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>constructivism</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>scaffolding</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>critical thinking</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>participation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>involvement in children's own learning</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>communicative competence</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>second language acquisition</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>bilingual education</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:description>The methodologies and approaches that are used in Spain to teach English as a second language seem to be obsolete now at the present moment, according to our position in the European ranking, what means that there is something that should be improved and researched. The aim of this project is to present, explain and compare two innovative methodologies which are now being introduced and established gradually, little by little, in Spain, having in mind the LOMCE (Ley Orgánica para la Mejora de la Calidad Educativa) and the European Frame Reference of Languages. These methodologies are Active Learning and Co-operative and collaborative learning, whose theoretical basis comes from constructivist and second language acquisition theories or frameworks. This dissertation makes reference as well to several experiences during my Erasmus stay last year in Aberdeen (Scotland), where I had the opportunity to observe and participate in first person how these two approaches were put into practice in different curricular subjects.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>