<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Villalba González, Marta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Calvo Pascual, Mónica</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Press and Politics by the Hand: the Manipulation of the British Press in the Scottish Road to Independence</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/31205</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:description>The research project that I present below aims to show a comparative analysis of seven British newspapers in order to determine what was the position of the press regarding the Scottish Referendum held on 18 September 2014. For this purpose, first I will proffer a review of the history of Scotland, from its beginnings as an independent kingdom until its settlement as a nation of the United Kingdom, to try to understand what the causes of the referendum might be. Then, I will make an introduction about the current political situation of Scotland and in relation to the press. To continue, I will provide a general explanation on the power of suggestion of the media that will lead me to a comparative analysis of a personal selection of headlines and articles from seven British newspapers. Finally, my essay will offer a very brief comment on the impact and meaning of the referendum to eventually conclude with the idea that, although the vast majority of newspapers preferred the union, I found it difficult to determine to what extent they sought to manipulate or rather just to inform due to their use of a very detached and indirect tone in their publications.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>