<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Martínez Bolea, Víctor</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vojar, Jiří</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Comparison of environmental characteristics and ecological value between technical reclamation and spontaneous succession on post-mining areas in Czech Republic</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/9151</dc:identifier>
  <dc:subject>coal mining</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>post-mining areas </dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>spoil banks </dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>ecological restoration </dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>technical reclamation </dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>spontaneous succession </dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>amphibians </dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>rana dalmatina </dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>czech republic </dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>north bohemian coal basin</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Due to decline of coal mining in Europe we found many post-mining areas in which we must carry out ecological restoration. At present, there are two main options; one hand, traditional technical reclamation and, other hand, innovative spontaneous succession. We compare both methods in order to know how environmental characteristics of resultant ponds are in each case. In addition, we analyze habitat preferences of Rana dalmatina under situations with high and poor abundance of clutches. Study area is North Bohemian Brown Coal Basin where we took data; then carry out statistical analysis. We found on spontaneous succesion areas a higher proportion of smaller shallow ponds, with gentle shore slopes, partial insolation of water surface and partial vegetation cover which characteristics are suitable for European amphibians. Also, when abundance of clutches is low the environmental characteristics of ponds as depth, vegetation cover, surrounding environment and status of reclamation are more important than with these levels are high. We conclude ponds on spontaneous succession have more suitable characteristics for amphibians (Rana dalmatina) than does technical reclamation; thus represent a wonderfull potential for nature conservation. Lastly, we want remember that there is a general decline in amphibian abundance so we must try to generate them the better environmental features for this situations.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>