<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Ruiz Gazulla, Carlota</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Igartua Arregui, Ernesto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Casas Cendoya, Ana M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Analizing sequence polymorphisms and HvFT1 expression in a biparental barley population</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/15231</dc:identifier>
  <dc:subject>barley</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>qtl</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>flowering time</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Time of flowering in barley has a large impact on yield, and many researches have focus on finding polymorphisms in genes underlying the adaptation of different cultivars to changing environmental conditions. Previous studies have identified three vernalization and two photoperiod genes, which have a major role in the determination of flowering. Other genes (HvFT1, HvCEN, HvELF3 or HvLUX) also contribute to fine tune the time to heading within spring or winter barley cultivars.  In this study we use a doubled haploid population, derived from the cross of two spring two-row barley cultivars, Beka and Logan. Previous QTL analyses had identified three major QTL controlling flowering time in this population. The aim of this study was to analyze the expression of three genes, HvELF3, HvCEN and HvFT1, candidates for the major QTLs segregating in this population. Gene expression was analyzed in eight doubled haploid lines with contrasting alleles for these genes. Plants with the Logan allele in the three genes flowered the earliest. Expression of HvFT1 was dependent on the genetic background. Higher HvFT1 expression, and earlier flowering, was detected in plants with the Logan allele in the three genes. Most of the results were coherent with the previous literature. La fecha de floración en la cebada tiene gran impacto  en la producción de las cosechas y por tanto, existe un interés por conocer los polimorfismos de los genes que están detrás de la adaptación de diferentes cultivares a ambientes con condiciones ambientales muy diversas. Estudios previos han identificado tres genes de vernalización y dos  de fotoperiodo, que juegan un papel importante en la determinación de la fecha de floración. Otros genes, (HvFT1, HvCEN, HvELF3 o HvLUX) también contribuyen a este fenómeno, tanto en variedades de primavera, como en las de verano. En este estudio hemos usado una población biparental, que deriva del cruce entre dos variedades de primavera, Beka y Logan. A partir de análisis de QTLs se han identificado tres QTL que controlan la fecha de floración en esta población. El objetivo de este estudio era analizar la expresión en los tres genes, HvELF, HvCEN y HvFT1; principales candidatos de los QTLs identificados. Se analizó la expresión en las ocho líneas de la población, las cuales, tenían diferente combinación de alelos cada una. Por un lado se vio como las plantas con alelos de Logan florecían antes. Además, las plantas que tenían  alelos de Logan para los tres genes, presentaban mayor expresión de HvFT1 que el resto. La mayoría de los resultados que se obtuvieron fueron coherentes con los observados en otros estudios similares.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>