<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Calvo Bautista, Jonathan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Corona Marzol, Isabel</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Applying a Translation Brief: The Translation Process of 'It's Time for an Urbanization Science'</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/15417</dc:identifier>
  <dc:subject>traducción</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Abstract Translation is very relevant nowadays because of the globalised society in which we live and the exchange of information. However, there is a great amount of information that belongs to different kinds of genres. This dissertation explores the field of translation from a professional point of view with the aim of focusing on this new communicative frame. To achieve that goal, a hypothetical brief is made by a Spanish magazine, which consists of an American journal article of 2,000 words approximately. The text was analysed according to a modified translation process based on Gouadec’s (2007) stages. Several different aspects of this process were necessary, including the textual analysis (Nord, 2005), the documentation, difficulties related to the translation (Hurtado Albir, 2001), translation procedures (Vázquez-Ayora, 1977), the adaptation to the brief and the revision of the translated text (Mossop, 2001). This information was classified within each category of each aspect, which served to produce a translation with the same information and purpose as the source text.  The most relevant findings were the differences presented between the English and the Spanish language. It could be said that the main problems that the translator had to face in this translation were the linguistic choices—62% of all the problems—related to style and language. Regarding the translation strategies, it could be said that the most frequent was the transposition—35% of the strategies used in the text. All of these findings point to the fact that each translation has its own characteristics and need different strategies to accomplish the translation. In addition, translation also allows the reader to analyse an English text with the result of learning more about the language and enrich the translator’s knowledge.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>