<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>García Cebollada, Héctor</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sancho Sanz, Javier</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Velázquez Campoy, Adrián</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Prototipo de aplicación bioinformática para estabilizar proteínas de manera racional</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/63665</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Increasing the stability of proteins is important for several applications, such as the production and storage of diagnostic kits and antibodies for therapeutic use or the industrial enzymatic catalysis in processes at high temperature. For this reason, several approaches have been used to predict the effects on stability of a mutation. However, all current programs can only predict the effect of a mutation given by the user. In this Master thesis, a method based on simple rational and empirical rules that both proposes mutations and predicts qualitatively their effect in stability is developed. Rules used for this program focus both on structural features (composition of alpha-helices, disulphide bonds, exposed acidic hydrogen-bonded residues, overexposed apolar residues, buried polar residues, steric clashes and internal cavities) and on the sequence of the protein (calculation of a consensus and an ancestral sequences). Mutations are then evaluated with a logistic regression model trained using machine learning techniques with a training group obtained from ProTherm database. The accuracy of the model is tested with another group of mutations obtained in ProTherm, reaching a higher accuracy than current methods. Finally, a user-friendly input and output format is developed for a general use of the program in research. ________________________________________________________________________________________________________________________________________________________ Aumentar la estabilidad proteica es importante para diversas aplicaciones, como la producción y almacenamiento de kits diagnósticos y anticuerpos con uso terapéutico o la catálisis enzimática en procesos industriales a alta temperatura. Por ello se han usado diversas aproximaciones para predecir los efectos en la estabilidad de una mutación. Sin embargo, los programas actuales solo predicen el efecto de una mutación introducida por el usuario. En este trabajo fin de Máster, se ha desarrollado un método basado en reglas empíricas y racionales simples que propone mutaciones y predice cualitativamente su efecto en la estabilidad. Las reglas utilizadas en el programa comprenden tanto propiedades estructurales (composición de hélices alfa, puentes disulfuro, residuos ácidos expuestos con puentes de hidrógeno, residuos apolares hiperexpuestos y polares enterrados, choques estéricos y cavidades internas) como de la secuencia (cálculo de las secuencias consenso y ancestral). Posteriormente, las mutaciones son evaluadas con un modelo de regresión logística entrenado mediante machine learning con un grupo de mutaciones obtenido de la base de datos ProTherm. La precisión del programa se calcula con otro grupo de mutaciones de ProTherm, alcanzando valores superiores a los de los métodos actuales. Finalmente, se han desarrollado formatos de entrada y salida de información sencillos para que cualquier usuario básico del campo de la investigación lo pueda usar.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>