<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Sirón Bolea, José María</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frías Corredor, Carmen</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>El final de la Restauración en Huesca</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/31140</dc:identifier>
  <dc:subject>restauración</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>caciquismo</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>elecciones</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>clientelismo</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>huesca</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>partidos políticos</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>políticos</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:description>RESUMEN En este trabajo se estudian las elecciones generales y provinciales en los distintos distritos de Huesca durante el periodo que va desde 1914 a 1923; el final de la Restauración.  Nos encontramos con una pugna entre partidos de notables en circunscripciones con muy pocos electores. La consecuencia de esto es que las ideologías y las políticas de ámbito nacional no tienen el peso suficiente para competir con unas políticas de carácter localista en las que priman las relaciones interpersonales. De aquí se deduce la importancia del conocimiento de las personas, de los políticos, para la interpretación de los procesos estudiados. En la primera parte de este trabajo se analizan los resultados de las elecciones atendiendo sobre todo a las alianzas entre los políticos que posibilitan esos resultados intentando siempre lograr acuerdos y evitar el conflicto. Acuerdos que suelen implicar a toda la provincia y rara vez un solo distrito. En la segunda parte hacemos un apunte prosopográfico para acercarnos a las personas que protagonizan políticamente este periodo para conocer su origen, posición, adscripción y evolución, entre otros aspectos. PALABRAS CLAVE Crisis de la Restauración, caciquismo, elecciones, clientelismo, Huesca, Partidos, políticos. ABSTRACT 	This research has been focus on general and provincial elections in the different districts of Huesca at the end of the Restauración; mainly this research studies the historical period between 1914 and 1923. 	The most characteristic feature of this period in a little province as Huesca is fights among different parties ruled by aristocrats (notables). As a little province, there were a few votes to fight for. The consequence of this background was the national ideologies and the different national politics didn’t have enough power to be the most important forces to rule the politic environment at Huesca. So interpersonal relationships were the most important fact to modify and built the local political environment at this province of Aragón. For this reason it has been really important for the researcher to know accuracy the different political characters and people around them to interpret the studied historical process.        The first part of this research analyzes the results of the elections in the mentioned historical period looking at the alliances between the main local politicians who allows that electoral results. Those alliances have shown the researcher that local politicians always tried to avoid any fight between them through those electoral agreements. Moreover, those alliances always were provincial alliances and almost never district alliances.  On the second part of this master’s thesis the researcher describes one by one the main historical and political characters of this historical period trying to discover their origins, social position, political assignment and evolution though the different events.     KEY WORDS Crisis of the Restoration, caciquismo, dominance of important locals, elections, clientelist, Huesca, political parties, politicians.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>