<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Jiménez Prieto, Raquel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lobera González, Maria Pilar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Balas Nieto, Francisco</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Análisis del impacto medioambiental y ocupacional de nanopartículas aerosolizadas en escenarios controlados.</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/63660</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Nanotechnology has become indispensable in the daily life. Nanomaterials are present in a lot of products, such as cloths, cosmetics, food industry and medicines among others. In the last decades, the production of nanomaterials has increased and so the exposure to such nanomaterials to workers and even customers. Moreover, it would be necessary to distinguish the ENMs from natural nanomatter that is already in the environment. In order to do that, labelling techniques have been used, particularly fluorescent labelling applied in SiO2 nanoparticles, which is one of the most used ENMs (mobile phones, cosmetics...etc.). 	Most of the researches are focused on the study of harmful ENMs uptaken through respiratory or ingestion route, but, what about the harm effects through cutaneous route? In this project surface contamination has been assessed using fluorescent Ru(phen)3:SiO2 NPs. 	Not only that, but it is necessary to catalogue these engineered nanomaterials (ENMs) and test the environmental, health and safety impact. Once ENMs are released into the environment, they suffer several abiotic and biotic interactions so it is not possible to know their fate and disposition. In this project, the toxicity of Ru(phen)3:SiO2 NPs have been tested in Chamydomonas reinhardtii; and aging process have been assessed within a case study focused on Ebro River basin physicochemical properties.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>