<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Rodrigo Fernández, Marina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martínez Falquina, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Challenging the Status Quo: Transmodernity and Hybridity in Tony Kushner’s Angels in America</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/47046</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:description>This thesis presents a study of the play by North American author Tony Kushner Angels in America: A Gay Fantasia on National Themes (1993), focused on the analysis of the character of Belize, an ex-ex-mulatto drag queen. After considering the various attempts by different authors at including this playwright within the categories of either Modernism or Postmodernism, that do not seem to properly fit into Kushner’s vision, I propose his categorization within the paradigm of Transmodernity, a term coined by Rosa María Rodríguez Magda which, as I contend, reflects the vision of the author in this pivotal work. Contrary to Modernist and Postmodernist visions of the text, this analysis proves how the sense of continuity and progress have more weight than the eschatological conception suggested by authors like Stanton B. Garner. Moreover, through the analysis of Belize from the perspective of the ‘other’ based on the concepts of race and genre that highlight his/her marginalization, we see how this character, a clear example of hybridity, can be apprehended from the perspective of relevant critical theories of the frontier. As a result, we observe the way in which Belize embodies the main ideas of Transmodernity since s/he incorporates a number of concepts that reflect the present moment in society. Este trabajo plantea un estudio de la obra teatral del escritor norteamericano Tony Kushner Angels in America: A Gay Fantasia on National Themes (1993), centrado en el análisis del personaje de Belize, un/a ex-ex-drag queen mulato/a. Tras examinar los diversos intentos por parte de varios autores de incluir a este dramaturgo bien en el paradigma del Modernismo, o bien en el del Postmodernismo, que no han terminado de encajar en la visión de Kushner, propongo su categorización dentro del paradigma de la Transmodernidad, término acuñado por la filósofa Rosa María Rodríguez Magda, y que a mi entender refleja la perspectiva del autor en esta obra clave. Frente a las visiones Modernistas y Postmodernistas del texto, en este análisis se demuestra cómo el sentido de la continuidad y progreso tiene mayor peso que la concepción escatológica propuesta por autores como Stanton B. Garner. Por otro lado, a través del análisis de Belize desde la perspectiva del ‘otro’ a partir de los conceptos de raza y género que subrayan su marginación, se relaciona a este personaje con las teorías de la frontera, presentándolo como un ejemplo claro de hibridismo. Como resultado, se observa el modo en que Belize personifica las principales ideas de la Transmodernidad pues incorpora una serie de conceptos que se ajustan al momento actual de la sociedad.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>