<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Cebollada Desentre, Javier</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>García Landa, José Ángel</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Musical Narrativities: Symbolising intertextualities and the musical characterization of the Tragic Hero in "An Equal Music" by Vikram Seth</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/47220</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Abstract The main purpose of this paper is to provide an in-depth analysis of the literary and musical references concerning symbolism and intertextuality in Vikram Seth’s An Equal Music as well as a portrayal of the tragic hero’s identity by means of musical associations. Hence, the analysis presents a point of connection between two disciplines that share blurred boundaries. Therefore, the approach taken in this paper aims to examine how music is represented in literature and how they are interrelated by means of allusions to both musical and literary works, concretely in the novel to deal with. Resumen El principal propósito de trabajo es mostrar un análisis exhaustivo de las referencias literarias y musicales con respecto al simbolismo e intertextualidad en An Equal Music de Vikram Seth, así como una descripción de la identidad del héroe trágico a través de asociaciones musicales. Así, el análisis presenta un punto de conexión entre dos disciplinas que comparten fronteras indefinidas. Por lo tanto, el enfoque adoptado en este trabajo tiene por objetivo estudiar cómo se representa la música en la literatura y cómo se interrelacionan ambas ambos por medio de alusiones a obras tanto musicales como literarias, concretamente en la novela a tratar.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>