<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Rodríguez Marco, Alejandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mur Dueñas, Mª Pilar</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Analysis of an English Coursebook and Its Oral Activities</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/11454</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:description>In this dissertation I will try to find out if a particular coursebook –New English File: Intermediate, NEF– is an appropriate coursebook to foster students’ oral skills in general and in a particular educational context. For this purpose, I will analyse and evaluate the coursebook, and then I will analyse and evaluate those activities which develop oral skills –listening and speaking activities– according to a specific criterion which will be developed in the Method section. I will first review both input and output hypotheses in general terms, discuss the advantages and disadvantages of using a coursebook in the EFL classroom, and reflect upon the most important factors for the selection of an appropriate coursebook and activities which foster the students’ oral communicative competence. Stephen Krashen and Merrill Swain have a very important role in language acquisition and learning and that is the reason why I find it necessary to review their theories. Similarly, Littlewood’s research on and classification of communicative activities is worth considering and they will certainly make the analysis easier. This particular theoretical part will not only be useful for this dissertation analysis, it is also a good reflection for any teacher on the design and on the characteristics of oral communicative activities.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>