<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Costas Ramón, Santiago</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pardo Jimeno, Julián</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Santiago García, Llipsy</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Analysis of the role of Granzyme-A in the development of colorectal cancer stem cells</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/58793</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2016</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Colorectal cancer is the third leading cause of cancer death worldwide with nearly 150.000 new cases diagnose annually. New therapies have been developed for the last years targeting different proliferation and survival signalling pathways but few advances have been done to avoid relapse in patients. Cancer stem cells are proposed as the main mechanism of resistance in current therapies. These cells have been described as a subset among all the tumour cell populations which have stemness properties such as self-renewal and differentiation capabilities. These features allow them to survive after antitumour treatments and regenerate the entire tumour mass. Also, cancer stem cells have been proposed as the responsible of metastasis.  Inflammation in colorectal cancer is a sign of poor prognosis and it has been proposed as the main driver of the tumour progression. Its relation with cancer stem cells has not been clasified yet but pro-inflammatory molecules such as TNF-α or IL-1B are able to activate cancer stem cells-related signalling pathways such as Wnt or Notch pathways. Granzyme-A, a protease released by immune cells, is involved in implication during like bacterial sepsis or arthritis. Our preliminary data indicate it is involved in development of colorectal cancer.  The current study analyse the implication of Granzyme-A in the activation of CSCs during inflammation-associated colorectal cancer in a mouse model.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>