<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Villuendas Romeo, Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>de Marcos Ruiz, Susana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Galbán Bernal, Francisco Javier</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>(Nano)biosensores ópticos enzimáticos basados en la síntesis "in situ" de nanoclusters</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/63659</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Nowadays food quality controls are very strict to ensure human health. There are many of them, to detect ripening, based on the determination of histamine (a biogenic amine), but there is not anyone based on putrescine and/or cadaverine. The aim of this project is to detect and quantify, if it is possible, those biogenic amines taking advantage of the enzymatic reaction between them and diamine oxidase, DAO. The product of this reaction turns into its cyclic form and forms a complex with a gold precursor. This is the beginning of the gold nanoparticles (AuNPs) synthesis, which can be measured by absorbance due to its optical properties based on the surface plasmon resonance (SPR) phenomenon. Therefore, absorbance due to nanoparticles can be related to biogenic amine’s concentration. In addition, a characterization is done to improve the conditions and the throughput of the reaction taking advantage of the reaction kinetics. Some experiments are proposed to understand the mechanism of the gold nanoparticles formation and, real and synthetic samples are analysed. The final purpose of this investigation line is to fabricate a biosensor to be implemented in food packages; therefore, the characterization is also done at room temperature to mimic real conditions.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>