<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Ruiz Sánchez, Yudit</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Plo Alastrué, Ramón</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>"Reduce Stress to Increase Vitality" Trabajo de traducción de un texto divulgativo</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/31111</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:description>This work is focused on the translation to Castilian Spanish from a chapter of the book by Brendan Brazier Thrive, the Vegan Nutrition Guide to Optimal Performance in Sports and Life. The chapter selected, Reduce Stress to Increase Vitality offers an interesting summary of the effects of stress and diet on the health of individuals. This section has its own linguistic style that is not only incredibly informative, but also contains many specialized terms which make the writing colorful and engaging. The following written chapters take us through different phases of the process of translation, from the analysis of the previous Original Text to the definitive layout of the Target Text. It was constructed through extensive research, compiling a strong bibliography, revision, and linguistic analysis of the first drafts. First and foremost, I will reflect on the rigor of the translation process that accompanies a real translation order. Secondly, I demonstrate my mastery over the methodology learned during the academic period of 2013-2014 in the Master of Translation of Specialized Texts.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>