<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Masip Solano, Marta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Serrano Cinca, Carlos</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Investment projects and financial viability. </dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/63902</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
  <dc:description>In the Interior Design industry, there is often a fear of buying new products because it does not exist any kind of program that shows exactly how the final decoration will look. The industrial design is nowadays just offering 2-D planes that are very far from showing a realistic view. There are only a few companies that offer 3-D computer programs, but even those are not accurate at all and they have many limitations.  On the other hand, there is a promising technology; the augmented reality, which adds virtual information to the existing physical information and which has great advantages. Due to this reason, I did not want to lose the opportunity of using augmented reality to give to all customers the possibility to be sure of their purchase, and at the same time to help interior design businesses to increase their sales by having this augmented reality service available in their stores. This technology has been already used in different fields of life and it has become one of the most revolutionary technologies of the moment and with the highest boom of popularity. Although, at the same time, this technology is still to be developed in the interior design industry and, in addition, it has a wide range of possibilities for the future that I want to consider for my business and I will explain in this document. Nowadays, when someone wants to make a purchase of furniture for a house, they have to mentally imagine how the new furniture will look in the house, they could measure the sizes of the new furniture and calculate if it fits in the space that they have saved for it, but they will never be sure if it would match with the whole decoration because it is very difficult to imagine it perfectly. Even if a 3D computer program is used to see the final look of the new room, it will not be as realistic as if they could use Augmented Reality glasses to see it.  My proposal for the new business is to create a software that transforms a video taken from a mobile device into an augmented reality video. In this way, anyone could record a video of their home, recording a panoramic view of each room and with our software, furniture shops, real state agents, or any business of the sector could transform that video into an augmented reality video, that with the help of the augmented reality glasses that person would be able to observe how the new furniture will look in their houses. This company (TECNOLIS) will be created in a period of technological advances and globalization, and I want to compete in a global market. This is why I will accept any means of payment contrasted as a payment through mobile, Bitcoin between others. My Main goal for this project is to create a business plan to know if my business idea could be profitable or not in the future. I have tried to choose an innovative business idea, which at first sight has many possibilities to succeed in the future. To get this I will firstly study the general and specific environment of the company.  After this I want to study the different strategies that I will follow in marketing, human resources and logistics. Finally, I will make a financial analysis to know if the project is viable economically, because the initial budget of the project is not going to be very high, it might increase when the first positive results of the company appear.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>