<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Ratia Loncán, Guillermo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baelo Allué, Sonia</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Naturalism and the Inevitability of Fate: Maggie: A Girl of the Streets and Sister Carrie</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/47267</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:description>ABSTRACT The purpose of this essay is to analyze and compare two novels written at the turn of the 20th century that are usually classified as naturalist: Maggie: A Girl of the Streets (1893) by Stephen Crane and Sister Carrie (1900) by Theodore Dreiser. More specifically, I will compare the main characters of each novel (Maggie Johnson and Carrie Meeber), taking into account the deterministic and Social Darwinist ideas that are recurrent in Naturalism. My aim is to call attention to the fact that both heroines have, apparently, very different destinies, although both works were contemporary and are classified within the same literary genre: Maggie dies whereas Carrie succeeds in her acting career. However, the close reading of the texts and the analysis of the narrative voiced used will show that the endings that both authors give to their main protagonists may not be so different after all.  El objetivo de este ensayo es analizar y comparar dos novelas escritas a finales del siglo  XIX y que suelen enmarcarse dentro del Naturalismo: Maggie: A Girl of the Streets (1893), de Stephen Crane y Sister Carrie, de Theodore Dreiser. Más concretamente, compararé los personajes principales de cada novela (Maggie Johnson y Carrie Meeber), teniendo en cuenta algunas ideologías recurrentes en el naturalismo como el determinismo o el darwinismo social. Mi intención es resaltar que las dos heroínas tienen destinos aparentemente muy distintos (Maggie muere mientras que Carrie se convierte en una actriz famosa), a pesar de que los dos libros son contemporáneos y pertenecen al mismo género literario. Sin embargo, el análisis de los textos y de la voz narrativa muestra que los finales que los autores dan a las protagonistas no son tan diferentes al fin y al cabo.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>