<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Blasco Rincón, Carolina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Luzón Marco, María José</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>The use of ICTs to enrich CLIL courses and materials</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/62597</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
  <dc:description>New technologies are having an increasingly important role in the teaching and learning of languages. They are a useful tool in the CLIL classroom, since they help students to understand content which is taught in a foreign language. This dissertation aims to explore the benefits of ICTs in CLIL and how CLIL teaching and materials could be improved and enriched by using them. An interview with a teacher was carried out. From the answers given, a webpage with several online resources and activities was created. The proposal was implemented and results were drawn. ICTs were shown to help students understand the content, and online games and videos were preferred over the rest of materials. However, only 54 % of the participants used ICTs to revise and study the subject, and 87% assured they would use the webpage section with additional materials. Future studies should consider whether students are really encouraged to use ICTs to complement classroom materials since it has been shown they play a fundamental role in the teaching and learning of languages.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>