<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Sin Bagüés, Daniel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ceamanos Llorens, Roberto</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>El anarquismo y la cultura obrera española (1870-1936)</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/47371</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Resumen:  La  llegada  de  la  sociedad  industrial  a  Europa  trajo  consigo  multitud  de transformaciones  entre  las  que  podemos  destacar  la  formación  de  la  clase  obrera,  un nuevo estrato social, pero heredero de la cultura popular propia de la era preindustrial.Paralelamente,  las  ideologías  surgidas  de  la  crítica  a  dicha  sociedad,  buscaran  ganar adeptos  entre  las  crecientes  capas  obreras,  siendo  el  anarquismo  el  que  más  arraigo alcanzó en España. Hizo su aparición en torno a 1870, iniciando un fuerte despliegue propagandístico con el objetivo de reformar la cultura popular, asegurándose con ello las  condiciones  más  propicias  para  su  propagación.  Un  proceso  asimilable  a  todo  el  occidente industrial, donde no sólo se asiste a la trasformación de economía y sociedad, sino también de la cultura y las mentalidades.  Palabras  clave:  cultura,  España,  Edad  Contemporánea,  anarquismo,  clase  obrera, propaganda. Abstract:  The  arrival  of  industrial  society  in  Europe  brought  with  it  many transformations; among the most important ones we can highlight the formation of the working class, a new social stratum, but inheritor of the popular culture typical of the pre-industrial  era.  Meanwhile,  ideologies  which  appeared  due  to  the  critical  attitude toward  this  society  tried  to  find  a  way  to  win  followers  among  the  growing  working  class sectors. In Spain, anarchism was the most deep-seated. It appeared around 1870, initiating  huge  propaganda  dissemination  in  order  to  remodel  the  existing  popular culture,  thereby  ensuring  the  most  propitious  conditions  of  spread.  A  comparable process throughout the industrial Western world, and it was not only the transformation of economy and society, but also the transformation of culture and mentalities. Keywords: culture, Spain, Late Modern Period, anarchism, working class, propaganda.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>