<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Najes Pérez, Laura</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Canudo Sanagustín, José Ignacio</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>La transición Jurásico-Cretácico en el entorno de Camarillas y Aguilar del Alfambra (Teruel)</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/32329</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:description>This work is based in a geological study of a sector of Iberian Chain, which is situated between Ababuj and Aguilar del Alfambra villages (Teruel). The main objective is the characterization of Upper Jurassic-Lower Cretaceous transition in this area of Galve Sub-basin. It is has carried out the geological mapping and two stratigraphic columns in different parts of the study area. The Villar del Arzobispo and the El Castellar Formations traditionally represents the Upper Jurassic-Lower Cretaceous transition in this area. The stratigraphic columns made shown the existence of three distinct geological units: Villar del Arzobispo Formation (bioclastic and oolitic limestones with interbedded sandstones and claystones), “upper part of the Villar del Arzobispo” Formation (predominance of red claystone with some intercalation of limestone and sandstone) and the El Castellar Formation subdivided into two sections (an inferior part essentially clayey and a superior part consisting of an alternating limestone and marl). The limit into both Formations and the correlation of two columns has been established with a conglomeratic level, previously described in other sectors of Galve Sub-basin. The study of litologhy has been completed with a petrographic study of the most representative facies.  Another objective has been the paleontological study of fossils found in this area. They have been found isolated plates of Xinjiangchelydae indet (Quelonia), one fragment of dentary with tooth of Goniopholidae (Crocodilomorpha), one fragment of ischium of theropod (dinosaur) and fossil trunk identified as Araucariaceae indet. These discoveries demonstrate the richness fossil of these facies, also they are the first vertebrate and vegetal fossils described in the municipality of Aguilar del Alfambra. Furthermore, it has been described new sauropod ichnites, some of them with skin impression. The transition between the Jurassic and the Cretaceous in Ababuj and Aguilar del Alfambra is characterized by the changing of marine to transitional and continental environment. The field survey and aerial photography has permitted to recognize an unconformity between Villar del Arzobispo Formation and the “upper part of the Villar del Arzobispo” Formation traditionally considered in this area. Besides, it has been chosen the conglomeratic level, which constitutes the first strata of the Cretaceous, being that similar levels of conglomerates outcrops in the “upper part of the Villar del Arzobispo” Formation. Moreover, it has proposed the possible causes of the change of thickness of the “upper part of Villar del Arzobispo Formation” between the two profiles.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>