<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Basurhina, Yulyana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oria Gómez, Beatriz</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>The erotic thriller of the 1980s and 1990s: Examining the sexuality of the psychopathic woman in ​Fatal Attraction and ​Basic Instinct </dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/62681</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
  <dc:description>El objetivo de este ensayo es explorar la figura de la  mujer psicópata en las películas Atracción Fatal (1987) e Instinto Básico (1992), centrándose principalmente en cómo el conservadurismo de los años 80 y 90 y la reacción ideológica contra las mujeres independientes afectó a su  representación en el thriller erótico de la época. El ensayo examinará la sexualidad de la psicópata como arma principal para seducir a los hombres, así como lo que esta “peligrosa” sexualidad simboliza en el género del thriller erótico. En primer lugar, el ensayo se centrará en la figura de la mujer fatal como producto del ya mencionado “backlash” de finales del siglo XX. A continuación, se analizarán dos tipos diferentes de mujeres psicópatas, tomando como ejemplo a Alex Forrest (Glenn Close) y Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone) y centrándose en su sexualidad y caracterización psicopática como amenaza para los hombres. This essay explores the figure of the psycho femme fatale in Fatal Attraction (1987) and Basic Instinct (1992), focusing mostly on how the conservatism of the 80s and 90s and the backlash against independent women affected their representation in the erotic thriller of the end of the century.  The essay will also examine the sexuality of the female psychopath as her main weapon to seduce men, as well as what this dangerous sexuality symbolizes in the erotic thriller genre. Firstly, the essay will comment on the figure of the femme fatale in the erotic thriller as a product of the backlash ideology of the last decades of the 20th century. Secondly, it will analyze two different types of psycho women, taking as an example Alex Forrest (Glenn Close) and Catherine Tramell (Sharon Stone) and focusing on their sexuality and psychopathic characterization as dangerous for men.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>