<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Armentia Avila, Maitane</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gil, Victoria</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Teaching and Learning English as a Foreign Language through Multiple Intelligences</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/47685</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Nowadays, English is the most commonly spoken language all over the world. Actually, it is a subject that is being taught in almost every school of our country but not all of them do it in the same way. For instance, there are some that teach English as a foreign language (EFL) in a very traditional way while others are implementing new resources and strategies in order to improve learners’ level. One of the possibilities could be teaching EFL lessons through Multiple Intelligences (MI). This is a common option taken by many new-fangled methods but it can be done in many different ways. In this project I want to show one possibility called AMCO method which is based on innovation and focused on teaching English by reinforcing their emotional and social development and giving them tools in order to help them to become bright and multi-competent children.  I have analysed in further detail this method not just thoroughly researching its resources but also observing it in a real AMCO classroom.  After analysing it and taking Gardner´s MI theory into account, I have realized about many contradictions between them and afterwards, I have proposed suggestions for teaching EFL lessons for developing their full potential.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>