<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Lantero Escolar, Elena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martínez de la Fuente, Jesús</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hernández García, Yulán</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Functionalization of gold nanoparticles for cell transfection</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/30693</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Abstract This report focuses on gold nanoparticle functionalization and checks their capability to transfect cells with a DNA plasmid, so the possibilities of the gold nanoparticles as vehicles for gene therapy can be explored. The nanoparticles were covered with a short polymer as stabilizer and, by the formation of an amide bound, different molecules of interest were conjugated to interact with a plasmid. Cell viability in presence of those functionalized nanoparticles was checked, and, finally, a transfection assay was performed. Transfected cells produced EGFP (Enhanced Green Fluorescent Protein), so they could be identified with fluorescence microscopy. Though some cells were transfected, the amount is really low, so more optimizations of the functionalization would be required to improve the process efficiency. Resumen Con intención de explorar las posibilidades de las nanopartículas de oro como vehículos para terapia génica, este trabajo se centra en su funcionalización y en comprobar su capacidad para transfectar células con un plásmido de ADN. En la funcionalización se han recubierto las nanopartículas con un polímero de cadena corta como estabilizante, y a éste, mediante formación de grupos amina, se le han conjugado distintas moléculas de interés que puedan interactuar con un plásmido. También se ha comprobado la viabilidad de células Vero en presencia de las nanopartículas funcionalizadas, y por último se ha realizado un ensayo de transfección. Las células transfectadas producían EGFP (Enhanced Green Fluorescent Protein) para ser identificadas por microscopía de fluorescencia. Aunque algunas células sí que se transfectaron  en el proceso, la cantidad es muy baja, por lo que se requerirían optimizaciones de la funcionalización para incrementar la eficiencia del proceso.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>