<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Moner Lasheras, Roque</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jordan, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Development of a device for the positioning of a projectile in high speed magnetic weft insertion for weaving machines</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/64146</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Short version: The magnetic weft insertion for weaving machines is being developed to combine the advantages of common methods of weft insertions such as rapier, projectile and air-jet weaving. The novel method of weft insertion is currently being tested by the use of a demonstrator at ITA. To fulfil a yarn transport at target insertion speeds of up to 1000 insertions per minute central challenges have to be overcome. The safe positioning of the magnetic projectile for preparation of the weft insertion is one central challenge. Objective of this thesis: In present work a device for the safe positioning of the magnetic projectile is being developed. This device shall be able to avoid a loss of the magnetic projectile due to centrifugal forces in rotational areas of the moving path. Additionally the device shall be able to position the projectile correctly and smoothly for the initiation of next weft insertion at the target insertion speeds. Solution process: According to VDI 2221 a mechanical design process is being carried out. After a clarification of the task, requirements are identified. The investigation of the current set-up of the demonstrator is used to support the definition of requirements. Sub-sequently the investigation of necessary functions and their structure follows. This functional structure is then used to develop principle solutions and basic concepts to fulfil respective sub-functions. By evaluating the fulfilment of requirements of the developed concepts a selection of a combination of principal concepts is carried out. Thus a general concept is being described in preliminary layouts. Key results: Key results are a list of requirements for the developed device and a description of the respective functional structure. Additionally basic concepts are developed for the fulfilment of these functions. With regard to the fulfilment of requirements a combination of principal concepts is selected for the creation of preliminary layouts. These preliminary layouts are a basis for further creation of definitive layouts and the manufacturing of functional models.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>