<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Nadela Puente, Sandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vázquez Orta, Ignacio</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Analysis of ironical moments from Friends according to Relevance Theory</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/15480</dc:identifier>
  <dc:subject>relevance theory</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>teoría pertinencia</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>dan sperber</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>deirdre wilson</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>pragmatics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>pragmática</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>friends</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>irony</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:description>One of the most ambitious aspirations in Pragmatics has always been to procure an explanation for the act of communication and the commands that rule our cognitive capacity in general, and the exceptional figures of speech, such as irony, in particular. The prevailing Relevance Theory by Sperber and Wilson, which is the theoretical framework that this paper aims to apply, has numerous and influential antecedents, of which Paul Grice’s Cooperative Principle is the most important. However, those theories have normally emphasized the theoretical dimension, since the examples shown by their authors have frequently been artificially conceived for fitting their purposes. This paper shows a more practical approach towards the selection and analysis of data by collecting ironical exchanges randomly extracted from the successful American sitcom Friends (Crane and Kauffman; 1994-2004) to carry out the analysis according to Sperber and Wilson’s theory. The analysis of the six heterogeneous extracts reveals that the entirety of the data fulfils the relevance theory’s requirements, so that all the ironical utterances can be interpreted with its help. This positive tendency to the observance of the theory in realistic data procures a hint of authenticity in the enforcement of Relevance Theory.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>