<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Navarro Bueno, Alberto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martínez Gómez, Francisco Javier</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Automation of profile packing</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/5216</dc:identifier>
  <dc:subject>Empaquetamiento</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Empaquetado</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Alumeco’s strategy is to be the most effective logistic partner through effective handling and warehousing of aluminium products. In order to achieve this goal, Alumeco has to be working with the newest technology and constantly improve processes and methods. In the central warehouse in Odense the activity is mainly based on two high rack systems. One high rack is for handling aluminium sheets and the other one is for profiles and bars. The weekly activity on the two high racks ismore than 1500 orderliness per week. (500 sheets and 1000 profiles and bars). Therefore, Alumeco wants to investigate the opportunity to automate the process of packing profiles and bars from the existing high rack. Today the handling and packing of profiles is carried out manually by the stock workers. It means that it is a heavy physical process. Summing up, the goal to this project must be: • A packing line that can handle 70% of all orderliness • No handling of material by hand or manual crane Getting these goals Alumeco will save money, they will increase their incomes and they will become the leader in the handling of aluminium profiles and bars because nowadays there are no factories with an automatic method. In this way one of the Alumeco’s strategies we will achieve: to be the most effective logistic partner through effective handling and warehousing of aluminium products.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>