<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Jover Latre, Noemí</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tarancon  de Francisco, Juan</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>When the World Falls Apart: Punk and 1970s Britain</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/65016</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
  <dc:description>ABSTRACT: From its birth punk rock has been considered a very negative music movement due to the nature of the music but also to the style of clothing and the attitude of musicians and fans alike. However, people tend to overlook that punk emerged from a specific social, political, cultural and economic context and that it must be considered in a dialogue with that context. Punk emerged in Britain in the seventies when the country was immersed in a deep economic and cultural crisis, in a decade characterized by a new right-wing conservatism that started to dismantle the welfare state and drove the working classes deeper into poverty. Talking into account this context of recession and social and cultural backlash, this dissertation considers the rise of punk rock and, more specifically, the first albums by the punk bands the Clash (The Clash) and the Sex Pistols (Never Mind the Bollocks, Here’s the Sex Pistols), both published in 1977, in an attempt to analyse how a new generation of disenfranchised and alienated youths  created a sense of identity by rebelling against a society that, at a time of crisis, instead of responding to the problems they faced, adopted measures that aggravated their situation.  RESUMEN: Desde su nacimiento, el movimiento punk rock ha sido visto de una forma muy negativa tanto por la forma de vestir y actitud de los fans y músicos como por las canciones escritas por estos. Sin embargo, se suele pasar por alto que el punk surgió de un contexto social, político, cultural y económico específico y que hay que ver su aparición en relación con éste contexto. El punk nace en los setenta en Gran Bretaña, una década en la que el país se encontraba en una gran crisis tanto económica como cultural, que llevó a que el conservadurismo de derechas cobrara más importancia, arrasando con el estado del bienestar y sumiendo a la clase trabajadora en una mayor pobreza. Teniendo en cuenta ésta época de recesión en la que hubo un retroceso cultural y social, este trabajo de fin de grado se centra en el nacimiento del punk y, más concretamente, los primeros álbumes de las bandas punk the Clash (The Clash) y the Sex Pistols (Never Mind the Bollocks, Here’s the Sex Pistols), ambos publicados en 1977, con el fin de analizar cómo una nueva generación de jóvenes aislados y olvidados por el resto de la población construyeron su identidad rebelándose contra una sociedad que en vez de intentar solucionar los problemas de éstos, tomo medidas que empeoraron su situación todavía más.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>