<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>LÓPEZ ARANA, JAVIER</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gil Imaz, Andrés</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lago San José, Marceliano</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>ORIGEN DE LA FRACTURACIÓN PRESENTE EN LOS CUERPOS ÍGNEOS (COLADAS Y SILLS), DE EDAD PÉRMICA, DEL SECTOR DE ATIENZA, NO DE LA RAMA CASTELLANA DE LA CORDILLERA IBÉRICA: FRACTURACIÓN TECTÓNICA “VS.” DISYUNCIÓN COLUMNAR.</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/60799</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
  <dc:description>A detailed study of fractures has been carried out along a subvolcanic andesitic sill and its sandstone host rock, both from the Permian in age. The studied sector is located in the north-western most part of the Iberian Chain, nearby Atienza (in the Guadalajara province, Spain). The detailed study of fractures has been carried out into 7 stations within the study area, wich roughly covers 50km2. This sector is known as an important sector of Lower Permian magmatic outcrops; characterized by volcanic and hypovolcanic materials.  The geochemistry of these magmatic intrusions and its chronological relations have been widely studied by different authors, such as Lago et al. (2004, 2005) and Majarena et al. (2015), defining a subvolcanic sill and subsequent volcanic intrusions, both andesitic with very similar petrological compositions. The materials of the subvolcanic sill are severely fractured by different joint families, nonetheless, is notable the lack of considerations about this characteristic and its origin. The structural analysis of joints, at outcrop-scale and by mean of stereographic projections, allows distinguishing the tectonic origin, caused by tectonic efforts, from magmatic, as result of the magma flow cooling. The goal of this paper is to determine the origin of the fractures, present in both the sill and in its host rock, by mean of its geometric and kinematic study, using structural analysis and, eventually, eventually, propose an evolutionary model arranging chronologically the different families. In order to constrein its primary or secondary origin, the data has been contrasted with other fracture families collected from more contemporany rocks such as red sandstones from Buntsandstein facies, whiyte-yellow sandstones of the Utrillas formation and upper Cretaceous limestones, presents in the local stratiigraphyc column.  A total of 8 fracture families have been distinguished from the igneous materials. The directional analysis combining with direct observations in the fields, have shown that the origin for families 4 is magmatic and contemporany with the magmatic event during the Lower Permian. On the other hand families 4, only identified in the sedimentary host rocks are considered caused by both syn-emplacement and subsequent tectonic efforts</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>