<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Theodoro Buratto, Rafaella</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oriol Langa, Luis</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Piñol Lacambra, Milagros</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Stimuli Responsive Polymeric Nanoparticles for Controlled Release of Cargo Molecules</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/32233</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Block copolymers (BCs) are complex macromolecules having, at least, two different polymeric chains chemically connected. These blocks are, in general, mutually immiscible, which leads to phase separation. Due to the length of the macromolecular blocks, this segregation occurs at the nanoscale. If BCs are formed by hydrophilic and hydrophobic blocks (amphiphilic BCs) these materials can undergo segregation in a selective solvent, e.g. water, resulting on micelles or vesicles above a critical concentration, as occurs with surfactants. Polymeric micelles or vesicles have higher stability than those formed by low molecular weight amphiphiles and have been explored in Medicine as nanocarriers for targeted drug delivery. Objective of this project is the preparation of nanoparticles from amphiphilic BCs to bond stimuli-responsive molecules by multiple hydrogen bonding (molecular recognition). Hydrophobic blocks having 2,6-diacylaminopyridine moieties will be employed for supramolecular assemblies. The high tendency to form polymeric nanoparticles of these BCs will be studied. Azobenzene groups will be easily incorporated to provide a light response to the nanoparticles that can be used for the release of cargo molecules. Furthermore, the presence of pyridine rings also provide of a pH response.  Tasks to be carried out in this project initially are: - Preparation of precursors and supramolecular amphiphilic BCs having 2,6-diacylaminopyridine groups.  - Complete characterization of the prepared materials, including spectroscopic and thermal analysis techniques. - Preparation of polymeric nanoparticles by using different methodologies and study by transmission electron microscopy.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>