<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Resa Polo, Borja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Beltrán Almería, Luis</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Sputnik, mi amor y la novela griega</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/62643</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
  <dc:description>La novela griega ha tenido una gran importancia en la historia de la literatura. Tanto es así, que podemos ver reflejada la huella de autores antiguos como Heliodoro de Emesa o Aquiles Tacio en la literatura actual. A lo largo de este trabajo analizaremos los aspectos que siguen vigentes y las diferencias que existen entre la novela griega y una obra actual como Sputnik, mi amor, cuyo nombre original es スプートニクの恋人 (Supûtoniku no koibito), del escritor japonés Haruki Murakami. Analizaremos esta obra de 1999 prestando gran atención a la comparativa con Las Etiópicas y Leucipa y Clitofonte, de Heliodoro y Tacio, respectivamente. Servirá de apoyo el estudio realizado por Bajtín Teoría y estética de la novela donde se recogen las principales características de la novela griega. PALABRAS CLAVE: novela griega, Heliodoro, Aquiles Tacio, Sputnik, mi amor, Haruki Murakami, Las Etiópicas, Leucipa y Clitofonte, Bajtín. Abstract The greek novel has had a great impact in the history of literature. So it has that we can see the ancient authors’ imprint such as Heliodorus of Emesa or Achilles Tatius reflected in the literature of today. The aim of this project is to analyse the prevailing elements and the differences between the greek novel and the current work Sputnik Sweetheart, whose original title is スプートニクの恋人 (Supûtoniku no koibito), by the japanese writer Haruki Murakami. We will examine this piece of work, written in 1999, paying close attention to the comparison with Ethiopian Story and Leucippe and Clitophon, by Heliodorus and Tatius, respectively. Besides, we will lean on the study Questions of Literature and Aesthetics, carried out by Bakhtin, which brings together the main features of the greek novel. KEYWORDS: greek novel, Heliodorus, Achilles Tatius, Sputnik Sweetheart, Haruki Murakami, Ethiopian Story, Leucippe and Clitophon, Bakhtin.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>