<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Serrano Oliván, Anabel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>García Labiano, Francisco Javier</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Diego Poza, Luis Francisco de</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Combustión de combustibles líquidos con captura de CO2 mediante transportadores sólidos de oxígeno basados en níquel</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/12833</dc:identifier>
  <dc:subject>chemical looping combustion</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>co2 capture</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>oxygen-carrier</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:description>Chemical Looping Combustion, CLC, is one of the most promising technologies for energy production plants and industrial applications with inherent CO2 capture which avoids the energy penalty present in other competing technologies. CLC combines power production with CO2 capture in a single process.  The CLC process is based on the transfer of oxygen from air to the fuel by means of a solid oxygen carrier, OC, avoiding direct contact between fuel and air. This work is focused on the study of the behavior of two different Ni-based OCs for its use in CLC applications with liquid fuels. As OC the system NiO/Al2O3 was selected because on the one hand NiO has already shown very high reactivity and good performance working at high temperatures and on the other hand Al2O3 has shown to be thermally stable with all types of fuel. Firstly, the influence of the main operating variables in the CLC process were studied in a batch fluidized bed using ethanol as model compound. The results show that the carbon deposition is minimized working at 950 ºC, molar ratio H2O/EtOH = 1 and reduction times between 45 and 90 seconds. Secondly, a theoretical model was developed in order to determine the main design parameters for a continuous CLC process working with liquid fuels. Different mass and heat balances were calculated with the purpose of establish a range of operating conditions where it is possible to operate with different liquid fuels (ethanol, ethylciclohexane and dodecane). Also, it was concluded that the use of these types of liquid fuels is feasible in a CLC process under conditions similar to those existing to gaseous fuels.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>