<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Alaiza Gil, Javier</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>El-Heliebi, Amin</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Optimización de una estrategia de sondas candado basadas en mRNA</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/64238</dc:identifier>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
  <dc:description>In situ padlock probes experiments are a common tool in single cell genomics. When applied to detect mRNA sequences, they allow quantification and localization of targeted transcript in each individual cell. These assays are mainly performed on cells attached to a glass slide or fixed tissue samples. However, if the padlock probes could be applied on cellular suspensions, the technique could be combined with a wide range of follow-up techniques, such as micromanipulation.  In order to test this, in situ padlock probing assays were performed on cellular suspensions and on cell seeded slides. The probes targeted mRNAs for β-actin and androgen receptor full length and were employed in three different cell lines: LNCaP, VCaP and HT-29. The results were observed by fluorescence microscopy and quantified by CellProfiler. In order to test the feasibility of a low coverage genetic sequencing, single cells were selected from the probed cellular suspension via micromanipulation, its DNA was amplified using whole genome amplification and the quality of the amplification product was verified by multiplex PCR.  In situ padlock probes assays could be applied to cellular suspensions and expression of the transcripts could be quantified and located in a similar manner to the methods for cells attached onto slides. The number of signals between both supports showed comparable results. Hence any further modifications of the protocol should be focused on improving its efficiency. DNA from probed cells might be of good quality to undergo sequencing. Los ensayos in situ de sondas candado son una herramienta común en genómica de células individuales. Cuando se utilizan para detectar secuencias de mRNA, permiten cuantificar y localizar la expresión del transcrito diana en cada célula individual. Estos ensayos se realizan principalmente en células adheridas a láminas de cristal y en muestras de tejido fijadas, sin embargo, si pudiesen ser aplicadas en células en suspensión, se podrían combinar con un amplio rango de técnicas, como por ejemplo la micromanipulación. Con objetivo de probar esto, se realizaron ensayos in situ de sondas candado en suspensiones celulares y en placas sembradas con células. Las sondas detectaban los mRNA de actina β y del receptor de andrógenos de longitud completa y fueron empleadas en tres líneas celulares distintas: LNCaP, VCaP y HT-29. Los resultados fueron observados en microscopio de fluorescencia y cuantificados usando CellProfiler. Para comprobar la posibilidad de usar una secuenciación de baja cobertura en muestras que hayan sufrido el sondeo, se seleccionaron células individuales mediante micromanipulación, su DNA fue amplificado usando secuenciación de genoma completo y la calidad del producto amplificado fue comprobada por PCR multiplex. El ensayo de sondeo in situ por sondas candado pudo ser aplicado a suspensiones celulares y sus resultados pudieron ser cuantificados y localizados usando métodos similares a aquellos utilizados en células adheridas. El número de señales detectadas mostró resultados comparables entre ambos soportes por lo que cualquier modificación posterior debería centrarse en mejorar su eficiencia. El material genético obtenido de células sondeadas podría tener la calidad suficiente para justificar la secuenciación.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>