<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Embid Wypysczyk, Patricia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Herrero Granado, María Dolores</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>The Heroine Who Felt Too Much: The Transition from Neoclassicism to Romanticism as Reflected in the Figure of Marianne Dashwood</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/15518</dc:identifier>
  <dc:subject>jane austen</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>sense and sensibility</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:description>This study intends to provide further insight and depth into the figure of Marianne Dashwood in the novel Sense and Sensibility, by Jane Austen. It will focus on how Romantic ideology is portrayed as a trap and severe danger for the heroine in the society of her time. In order to do that, this analysis will first consider the aim of the novel as regards Marianne’s evolution, to then study her in relation to her sister Elinor and the Romantic ideology that she so wonderfully seems to embody. Moreover, the use of language to express feelings and emotions will also be taken into account, as well as the environment in which Marianne has been brought up and the figure of Mrs. Dashwood, her mother. The conclusion that can be reached is that, in this novel, excessive feelings are shown as being rather dangerous, even life-threatening, in this transitional period (from Neoclassicism to Romanticism). On the whole, this is a didactic novel that strives to make it clear that some Neoclassical elements, such as endurance and decorum, are always to be preserved at all costs.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>