<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Viamonte Dominguez, Juan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rubio Navarro, Carlos Enrique</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>Determination of aspartame in soft drinks using HPLC</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/8587</dc:identifier>
  <dc:subject>determination</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>aspartame</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>soft drinks</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>hplc</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>artificial</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>sweetener</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:description>The aim of this project is to determine the levels of aspartame in various cola products using High Pressure Liquid Chromatography (HPLC). Four different cola brands are examined, Coca-Cola Zero, Coca-Cola Light, Pepsi Max and Harboe Cola Minus. There is written a section of theory about aspartame, the environment and legislation for the substance. Additionally, there is made a theoretical section on HPLC and statistics. In the laboratory, a method for the examination of the aspartame in the coke product is created. This method is used to collect data for the various fabricates which are examined using various statistical parameters. In method development, it is found that aspartame can be separated completely from the other ingredients of the cola products. Aspartame content is verified by means of a certified standard substance. In the laboratory an Agilent HPLC is used with a C-18 column, 150 mm long and a particle diameter of 5 micrometers. The method uses a gradient program of acetonitrile and 22 mM phosphate buffer pH 2.5. The method is confirmed by statistical calculations that show that the data for the same cola is both repeatable and reproducible. Through tests of newer colas of the same brands, it is shown that the concentration of aspartame in the same brand vary significantly from bottle to bottle. The recovery of the method is close to 100 %, which is extremely essential for the validation of the method.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/masterThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>