<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:creator>Puig Cascajo, Beatriz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lafuente Millán, Enrique</dc:creator>
  <dc:title>The use of games to promote the Second Language Acquisition</dc:title>
  <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/16864</dc:identifier>
  <dc:subject>games</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>methodology </dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>sla</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>focus on meaning</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>communicative competence</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>bilingual teachers</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>bilingual education</dc:subject>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:description>A considerable amount of research and publications have dealt with games in Infant and Primary Education. Nevertheless, little is known about the role games can play in Foreign Language Acquisition with young learners. The aim of this project is to investigate how Infant Education teachers use them to promote SLA and whether   their use can help to achieve this objective. Firstly, this study briefly reviews the techniques of English teaching and how these can influence the use of games. Subsequently, key theories and research concerned with the importance of games in Infant Education, are reviewed, as well as the suitability of using games as a methodology for teaching English. Moreover, eight games provided by several teachers from bilingual schools are analyzed and the extent to which they promote the SLA is evaluated. Finally, data from interviews with two teachers is examined to investigate their opinion about games as an educational method.</dc:description>
  <dc:format>pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
  <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/bachelorThesis</dc:type>
  <dc:rights>by-nc-sa</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>